Guide to the John C. Calhoun Newton Papers, 1870-1931 RL.10132
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John C. Calhoun Newton papers
1870-1931
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Newton, John C. Calhoun
RL.10132
8 Linear Feet 16 boxes, 3,732 items (including 132 vols.)
This collection contains letters and papers of John Caldwell Calhoun Newton, a Methodist minister and missionary to Japan, concerning his education at Kentucky Wesleyan College, Kentucky Military Institute, and Johns Hopkins University; his experience as a minister in Kentucky and Virginia; and his career as dean of the theological school at Kwansei Gakuin Union Mission College and Seminary in Kobe, Japan, 1888-1897, and president of that institution, 1913-1923.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical Note
John Caldwell Calhoun Newton spent his career as a minister, missionary, and college professor in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.
Provenance
The John C. Calhoun Newton Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1944.
Collection Overview
This collection contains letters and papers of John Caldwell Calhoun Newton, a Methodist minister and missionary to Japan, concerning his education at Kentucky Wesleyan College, Kentucky Military Institute, and Johns Hopkins University; his experience as a minister in Kentucky and Virginia; and his career as dean of the theological school at Kwansei Gakuin Union Mission College and Seminary in Kobe, Japan, 1888-1897, and president of that institution, 1913-1923.
Papers contain family letters and correspondence with mission leaders of the church in America and missionaries of all churches in Japan. Volumes include sermon and lecture notes, some in Japanese; notebooks on courses Newton taught or had taken as a student, including 5 volumes of notes taken at Johns Hopkins University on G. Stanley Hall's lectures on philosophy, education, psychology, and psycho-physics, and one volume of notes on a history course taught by Herbert Baxter Adams; a Kwansei Gakuin classbook; a list of subscribers to the Twentieth Century Educational Fund of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South; a book of Kwansei Gakuin accounts; diaries, 1868-1869 and 1869-1879; a scrapbook; journals, 1881, 1888, and 1924; memoranda books, 1886-1888, 1889-1890, 1895-1896, 1898, and 1899-1900; pastor's books for Hillsboro, Kentucky, 1876-1877, Somerset, Kentucky, 1878-1879, Carlisle, Kentucky, 1879-1881, and Portsmouth, Virginia, 1900-1901; and notes on the scriptures and Newton's reading, including a large amount on the history of Scotland, Ireland, and Great Britain.
Japan -- Religion; Missions -- Japan; Methodist Church -- Sermons; Methodist Episcopal Church, South -- Clergy -- Correspondence; Methodist Episcopal Church, South -- Missions; Adams, Herbert Baxter; Hall, G. Stanley (Granville Stanley); Newton, John C. Calhoun
- John C. Calhoun Newton papers, 1870-1931
  - Correspondence, 1872-1904; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1905-1907; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1908-1912; 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1913-1916; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1917-1927; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1928-1931 and undated; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Papers related to Kwansei Gakuin Academy and Kwansei Gakuin United Methodist College and Seminary, undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Biographical sketches, undated (Box 6)
  - Lectures and sermons: A-C, undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Lectures and sermons: C-E, undated; 8 folders (Box 7)
  - Lectures and sermons: E-J, undated; 6 folders (Box 8)
  - Lectures and sermons: M-U, undated; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Financial papers, undated (Box 9)
  - Clippings, 1898-1909 (Box 9)
  - Clippings, 1910-1930 and undated (Box 10)
  - Printed material (Box 10)
  - Miscellany (Box 11)
  - Printed material (Box 11)
  - Postcards (Box 11)
  - Accounts of Sustenance Fund (Kobe, Japan), 1903-1907; 10 pages (Box 11, Volume 3080)
  - Address Book (Kobe, Japan), undated; 70 pages (Box 11, Volume 3081)
  - Addresses, Sermons and Lectures (Kobe, Japan), undated; 198 pages (Box 11, Volume 3082)
  - Class Book (Kobe, Japan), undated; 7 pages (Box 11, Volume 3083)
  - Diary, 1868-1869 (Kobe, Japan), 192 pages (Box 11, Volume 3084)
  - Diary,1869-1879 (Kobe, Japan), 56 pages (Box 11, Volume 3085)
  - Illustrations for Sermons, 1887 (Kobe, Japan), 79 pages (Box 11, Volume 3086)
  - Journal, 1891 (Kobe, Japan), 44 pages (Box 11, Volume 3087)
  - Journal, 1888 (Kobe, Japan), 33 pages (Box 11, Volume 3088)
  - Journal, 1924 (Kobe, Japan), 150 pages (Box 11, Volume 3089)
  - Lecture Notes on Ethics, 1919-1920 (Kobe, Japan), 104 pages (Box 11, Volume 3090)
  - Lecture Notes on Ethics, 1922 (Kobe, Japan), 23 pages (Box 11, Volume 3091)
  - Lecture Notes on Ethics, (No. 1) 1930 (Kobe, Japan), 114 pages (Box 12, Volume 3092)
  - Lecture Notes on Christian Theism, 1890 (Kobe, Japan), 116 pages (Box 12, Volume 3093)
  - Lecture Notes on Modern Politics from Herbert B. Adams, 1884 (Kobe, Japan), 74 pages (Box 12, Volume 3094)
  - Lecture Notes on Philosophy and Ethics from Dr. George S. Morris (Kobe, Japan), undated; 70 pages (Box 12, Volume 3095)
  - Lecture Notes on "Politcal Reformers" from Herbert B. Adams, 1884 (Kobe, Japan), 72 pages (Box 12, Volume 3096)
  - Lecture Notes on Psycho-Physics by G. Stanley Hall, 1885-1886 (Kobe, Japan), 188 pages (Box 12, Volume 3097)
  - Lecture Notes on Theology, 1888-1889 (Kobe, Japan), 152 pages (Box 12, Volume 3098)
  - Lecture Notes on Theology (Kobe, Japan), undated; 93 pages (Box 12, Volume 3099)
  - Lectures on Christian Missions, 1925 (Kobe, Japan), 105 pages (Box 12, Volume 3100)
  - Lectures on Comparative Religion, 1894 (Kobe, Japan), 31 pages (Box 12, Volume 3101)
  - Lectures on Education from G. Stanley Hall, 1885 (Kobe, Japan), 86 pages (Box 12, Volume 3102)
  - Lectures on Ethics, 1921-1922 (Kobe, Japan), 62 pages (Box 12, Volume 3103)
  - Lectures on History of Christian Missions (Kobe, Japan), undated; 24 pages (Box 12, Volume 3104)
  - Lecture Notes on History of Philosophy from G. Stanley Hall, 1884-1885 (Kobe, Japan), 108 pages (Box 12, Volume 3105)
  - Memoranda, 1886-1888 (Kobe, Japan), 118 pages (Box 12, Volume 3106)
  - Memoranda, 1889-1890 (Kobe, Japan), 33 pages (Box 12, Volume 3107)
  - Memoranda, 1895-1896 (Kobe, Japan), 72 pages (Box 12, Volume 3108)
  - Memoranda, 1898 (Kobe, Japan), 64 pages (Box 12, Volume 3109)
  - Memoranda, 1899-1900 (kobe, Japan), 56 pages (Box 12, Volume 3110)
  - Memoranda (Kobe, Japan), undated; 8 pages (Box 12, Volume 3111)
  - Memoranda (Kobe, Japan), undated; 90 pages (Box 12, Volume 3112)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1885 (Kobe, Japan), 105 pages (Box 13, Volume 3113)
  - Miscellaneous, Notes, 1886 (Kobe, Japan), 101 pages (Box 13, Volume 3114)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 38 pages (Box 13, Volume 3115)
  - Notes, 1894 (Kobe, Japan), 45 pages (Box 13, Volume 3116)
  - Notes, 1920 (Kobe, Japan), 6 pages (Box 13, Volume 3117)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 100 pages (Box 13, Volume 3118)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 14 pages (Box 13, Volume 3119)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 77 pages (Box 13, Volume 3120)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 81 pages (Box 13, Volume 3121)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 61 pages (Box 13, Volume 3122)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 50 pages (Box 13, Volume 3123)
  - Notes (Kobe, Japan), undated; 47 pages (Box 13, Volume 3124)
  - Notes on Bible (Kobe, Japan), undated; 70 pages (Box 13, Volume 3126)
  - Notes on Buddhism, 1886 (Kobe, Japan), 56 pages (Box 13, Volume 3127)
  - Notes on Calvinism, 1881 (Kobe, Japan), 41 pages (Box 13, Volume 3128)
  - Notes on China etc. (No. 1) (Kobe, Japan), undated; 108 pages (Box 13, Volume 3129)
  - Notes on China (No. 3) (Kobe, Japan), undated; 38 pages (Box 14, Volume 3130)
  - Notes on Christian Ethics (Kobe, Japan), undated; 74 pages (Box 14, Volume 3131)
  - Notes on Christian Ethics (Kobe, Japan), undated; 57 pages (Box 14, Volume 3132)
  - Notes on Church History (Kobe, Japan), 1888-1889; 86 pages (Box 14, Volume 3133)
  - Notes on Church History (Kobe, Japan), 1888-1889; 152 pages (Box 14, Volume 3134)
  - Notes on Early Britain, (No. I), undated; 51 pages (Box 14, Volume 3135)
  - Notes on Early Britain (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3136)
  - Notes on Early Christianity in Ireland, Gaul and Britain, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3137)
  - Notes on Early Christianity in Ireland, Gaul and Britain, (No. 2) (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3138)
  - Notes of the Economic History of China, (No. 2) (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3139)
  - Notes in Japanese (Kobe, Japan), 1920 (Box 14, Volume 3140)
  - Notes on Exegesis of Genesis, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3141)
  - Notes on Greek Mythology, (Kobe, Japan) (Box 14, Volume 3142)
  - Notes on Greek Philosophy, (Kobe, Japan), 1884 (Box 14, Volume 3143)
  - Notes on Greek Religion and Mythology, (Kobe, Japan), 1883 (Box 14, Volume 3144)
  - Notes on History from Herbert B. Adams, (Kobe, Japan), 1885 (Box 14, Volume 3145)
  - Notes on History of Foreign Missions, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3146)
  - Notes on Ireland, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3147)
  - Notes on Ireland, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3148)
  - Notes on Ireland and England, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3149)
  - Notes on Irish Statesmen, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3150)
  - Notes on Medieval History from herbert B. Adams, (Kobe, Japan), 1884 (Box 14, Volume 3151)
  - Notes on Missions in Japan, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3152)
  - Notes on New Testament Exegesis, (Kobe, Japan), 1889 (Box 14, Volume 3153)
  - Notes on the Old Testament, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3154)
  - Notes on Old Testament Exegesis, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3155)
  - Notes on Old Testament Exegesis, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3156)
  - Notes on Old Testament Exegesis, (Kobe, Japan), 1888-1889 (Box 15, Volume 3157)
  - Old Testament Exegesis, (Kobe, Japan), 1888-1889 (Box 15, Volume 3158)
  - Notes on Oriental Countries, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3159)
  - Notes on Pedagogy (in Japanese), (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3160)
  - Notes on Philosophy, Notes on Christian Ethics, (John Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland and Atlanta, Georgia), 1883-1884; 1930 (Box 15, Volume 3161)
  - Notes on the Psalms, (Kobe, Japan), 1909 (Box 15, Volume 3162)
  - Notes on Psychology from G. Stanley Hall, (Kobe, Japan), 1884 (Box 15, Volume 3163)
  - Notes on Readings, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3164)
  - Notes on Readings, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3165)
  - Notes on Readings, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3166)
  - Notes on Readings, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3167)
  - Reading Notes, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3168)
  - Notes from Readings, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3169)
  - Notes on Regulse Fidel Ecclesiae Ante-Nicenae at Nicense, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3170)
  - Notes on Roman History, (Kobe, Japan), 1887 (Box 15, Volume 3171)
  - Notes on Roman Occupation of Britain, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3172)
  - Notes on Scotland (No. I), (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3173)
  - Notes on Scotland (No. 2), (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3174)
  - Notes on Scotland (no.II), (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 15, Volume 3175)
  - Notes for Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), 1875 (Box 15, Volume 3176)
  - Notes on Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), 1886 (Box 15, Volume 3177)
  - Notes for Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), 1887 (Box 15, Volume 3178)
  - Notes for Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), 1896 (Box 15, Volume 3179)
  - Notes for Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), 1900-1901 (Box 15, Volume 3180)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), 1885 (Box 15, Volume 3181)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), 1891 (Box 15, Volume 3182)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), 1902 (Box 16, Volume 3183)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), 1916 (Box 16, Volume 3184)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3185)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3186)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3187)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3188)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3189)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3190)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3191)
  - Notes on Theology, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3192)
  - Notes, Sermons, Addresses, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 14, Volume 3125)
  - Pastor's Record, (Kobe, Japan), 1876-1877 (Box 16, Volume 3195)
  - Pastor's Book, (Kobe, Japan), 1879-1880 (Box 16, Volume 3194)
  - Pastor's Record, (Kobe, Japan), 1878-1879 (Box 16, Volume 3195)
  - Pastor's Book, (Kobe, Japan), 1880-1881 (Box 16, Volume 3196)
  - Pastor's Book, (Kobe, Japan), 1900-1901 (Box 16, Volume 3197)
  - Psychology Notes from Lectures of G. Stanley Hall, (Kobe, Japan), 1885 (Box 16, Volume 3198)
  - Quotation Book, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3199)
  - Records for Kwansei Gakuin, (Kobe, Japan), 1916-1917 (Box 16, Volume 3200)
  - Scrap Book, (Kobe, Japan), 1879-1895 (Box 16, Volume 3201)
  - Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), 1878-1880 (Box 16, Volume 3202)
  - Sermon Book, (V.P.), 1899-1901 (Box 16, Volume 3203)
  - Sermon Book, (Kobe, Japan), 1900-1901 (Box 16, Volume 3204)
  - Sermons in Japanese and English, (Kobe, Japan), 1905 (Box 16, Volume 3205)
  - Sermons and Lectures, (Kobe, Japan), 1927 (Box 16, Volume 3206)
  - Sermons, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3207)
  - Sermon Book, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3208)
  - Subscription to Twentieth Century Educational Fund of the M.E. Church, South, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3209)
  - Sunday School Normal Course, (Kobe, Japan), undated (Box 16, Volume 3210)